<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dr. Marissa Barlaz</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dr. Marissa Barlaz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Mining with R</title>
      <link>/portfolio/textminingr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/textminingr/</guid>
      <description>Setting up an API Mining and Processing Searching for tweets  Comparing three Twitter Users Processing Data Word Ratios Frequencies of key words Sentiment analysis  Comparing tweets with certain search terms Processing data Locations and time series  Another example of multiple search terms Time and Space Sentiments  A few final words   Setting up an API The first thing to do with R when getting ready to do Twitter mining is to set up your credentials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Graphing Workshop</title>
      <link>/portfolio/rgraphingworkshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/rgraphingworkshop/</guid>
      <description>Data Aesthetics Faceting Statistical Transformations Other Aspects of the graph Colors  Wrapping up   The aim of this workshop is to teach you the ins and outs of using the ggplot2 package in R.
The materials for this workshop can be found here.
A lot of the information in this workshop is based on workshops given at Harvard: https://dss.iq.harvard.edu/workshop-materials
Please make good use of the following cheat sheet!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Processing with the Tidyverse</title>
      <link>/portfolio/dataprocessing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/dataprocessing/</guid>
      <description>Why the tidyverse? Tidy data Components of the tidyverse Importing data The pipe operator  Data Manipulation with dplyr Filter Arrange Select Mutate group_by Summarise  Tidying data with tidyr Shapes of data Gather Spread Separate Unite  Relating different data sets with dplyr Mutating Joins Filtering joins  My data processing code   Why the tidyverse? There are a few reasons to use R and the Tidyverse for data processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to R and RMarkdown</title>
      <link>/portfolio/intror/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/intror/</guid>
      <description>R as a calculator Variables Functions Data Frames Subsetting RMarkdown Formatting Bullet Points   #Welcome to R! You might be asking, why should I use R instead of another type of software? In addition to being able to do statistics (like in Minitab, SPSS, Stata, etc.), you can do high-level scripting, statistical programming, and exploratory data analysis in R. It is free and open-source, meaning there is a large community of contributors and users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Modeling Workshop</title>
      <link>/portfolio/rmodelingworkshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/rmodelingworkshop/</guid>
      <description>What is the point? Data Simple linear regression Moving beyond simple linear regression Interactions Categorical Predictors Predicting Values Binary Outcomes  Polynomial Regression Mixed Effects Models   The aim of this workshop is to teach you the basics of statistical models in R.
The materials for this workshop can be found here.
What is the point? When looking at data, we want to determine if there is a relationship between our independent and dependent variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAM in R</title>
      <link>/portfolio/gam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/gam/</guid>
      <description>Packages Data What is a generalized additive model? Running a GAM in R Fitting a basic GAM Visualizing GAM results Random effects Random intercepts Random slopes Random factor smooths   Other topics to consider   Packages The packages you will need for this workshop are as follows. I am also including the hex codes for a colorblind-friendly palette, which I use for my plots. I used the gganimate package to show my dissertation data (below), but this is not crucial for data processing/analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to LaTeX</title>
      <link>/portfolio/latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/latex/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to LaTeX What is LaTeX? What’s so great about LaTeX? What’s not so great about LaTeX? Editors  Basics of LaTeX Important symbols and commands  The preamble Document classes Page formatting Packages  Body Title page Sections Font styles Figures Tables  Bibliographies Other possibilities with LaTeX   Introduction to LaTeX What is LaTeX? LaTeX is a document preparation system, that is becoming the de-facto method in STEM fields, such as math, physics and computer science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>This is a &amp;ldquo;hello world&amp;rdquo; example website for the blogdown package. The theme was forked from @jrutheiser/hugo-lithium-theme and modified by Yihui Xie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phonetics Tools in R</title>
      <link>/portfolio/phoneticstools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/phoneticstools/</guid>
      <description>PraatR Pitch analysis  rPraat Using apply to create .Pitch files  PhonTools Pitch tracking Formant Tracking  Comparison and plotting F0 Plotting Formants - PhonR and ggplot PhonR ggplot2 Spectrograms with PhonTools    library(tidyverse) library(PraatR) library(rPraat) library(phonR) library(dygraphs) library(phonTools) library(audio) library(tuneR) library(gss) For this workshop, I will be using a subset of my dissertation data. I will be using words with oral vowels in Brazilian Portuguese (/a/ from the word babado, /i/ from the word cabido, and /u/ from the word tributo), repeated by five female speakers in a carrier phrase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phonetics Tools in R - Supplementary code</title>
      <link>/portfolio/phontools2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/phontools2/</guid>
      <description>Data processing PraatR  Dygraphs Create shorter examples from long audio Create dygraphs  Getting information from two tiers   Data processing library(tidyverse) ## ── Attaching packages ─────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────── tidyverse 1.2.1 ── ## ✔ ggplot2 3.0.0 ✔ purrr 0.2.5 ## ✔ tibble 1.4.2 ✔ dplyr 0.7.7 ## ✔ tidyr 0.8.1 ✔ stringr 1.3.1 ## ✔ readr 1.1.1 ✔ forcats 0.3.0 ## ── Conflicts ────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────── tidyverse_conflicts() ── ## ✖ dplyr::filter() masks stats::filter() ## ✖ dplyr::lag() masks stats::lag() library(PraatR) library(rPraat) library(phonR) library(dygraphs) library(phonTools) ## ## Attaching package: &amp;#39;phonTools&amp;#39; ## The following object is masked from &amp;#39;package:dplyr&amp;#39;: ## ## slice library(audio) ## ## Attaching package: &amp;#39;audio&amp;#39; ## The following object is masked from &amp;#39;package:phonTools&amp;#39;: ## ## play library(tuneR) ## ## Attaching package: &amp;#39;tuneR&amp;#39; ## The following object is masked from &amp;#39;package:audio&amp;#39;: ## ## play ## The following objects are masked from &amp;#39;package:phonTools&amp;#39;: ## ## normalize, play library(gss) absdir = &amp;quot;/Users/goldrch2/Desktop/Research/FemaleBP/&amp;quot; mydir = list.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>