<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolios on Dr. Marissa Barlaz</title>
    <link>/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Portfolios on Dr. Marissa Barlaz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>R Graphing Workshop</title>
      <link>/portfolio/rgraphingworkshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/rgraphingworkshop/</guid>
      <description>Data Aesthetics Faceting Statistical Transformations Other Aspects of the graph Colors Labels, titles, and Axes Theme  Wrapping up   The aim of this workshop is to teach you the ins and outs of using the ggplot2 package in R.
The materials for this workshop can be found here.
A lot of the information in this workshop is based on workshops given at Harvard: https://dss.iq.harvard.edu/workshop-materials
Please make good use of the following cheat sheet!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Processing with the Tidyverse</title>
      <link>/portfolio/dataprocessing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/dataprocessing/</guid>
      <description>Why the tidyverse? Tidy data Components of the tidyverse Importing data The pipe operator  Data Manipulation with dplyr Filter Arrange Select Mutate group_by Summarise  Tidying data with tidyr Shapes of data Gather Spread Separate Unite  Relating different data sets with dplyr Mutating Joins Filtering joins  My data processing code   Why the tidyverse? There are a few reasons to use R and the Tidyverse for data processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to R and RMarkdown</title>
      <link>/portfolio/intror/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/intror/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to R! What can we do with R? R as a calculator Variables Functions Packages  Types of data Data Frames Subsetting Loading data  RMarkdown RMarkdown Formatting Bullet Points Images Hyperlinks Tables and text formatting Formatting cheat sheet    Welcome to R! You might be asking, why should I use R instead of another type of software? In addition to being able to do statistics (like in Minitab, SPSS, Stata, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Modeling Workshop</title>
      <link>/portfolio/rmodelingworkshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/rmodelingworkshop/</guid>
      <description>What is the point? Data Simple linear regression Moving beyond simple linear regression Interactions Categorical Predictors Predicting Values Binary Outcomes  Polynomial Regression Mixed Effects Models   The aim of this workshop is to teach you the basics of statistical models in R.
The materials for this workshop can be found here.
What is the point? When looking at data, we want to determine if there is a relationship between our independent and dependent variables.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>